H. David Kaplan Performing Arts Collection
University of Houston Libraries
- Theatre, 1960s-1980s
  - Programs (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous, 1980-85, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Film
  Small series of news clippings, periodicals and programs devoted to film, American Film Theatre and presentation of "Napoleon" with Houston Grand Opera orchestra.
  - News clippings, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Periodicals: Miscellaneous, 1972, 1978, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Press Release: "Napoleon" (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Fliers (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - American Film Theatre Programs (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Miscellaneous, 1960s-1980s
  Printed materials (fliers, news clippings, periodicals, programs and schedules) for various performing arts venues, sports, community events and a scrapbook.
  - (Box 8)
    - Brightly colored still life by Herb Mears, inscribed to David Kaplan by artist (Box 8, Folder 10, Item 1)
    - Jim Dine: The Pace Gallery, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 10, Item 2)
  - Celebrity Autographs (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Festival Programs
    - (Box 8)
      - Aspen Music Festival, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 12, Item 1)
      - Carmel Bach Festival, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 12, Item 2)
      - Olympic Arts Festival, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 12, Item 3)
      - Spoleto Festival, 1978, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 12, Item 4)
      - Tanglewood Berkshire Festival, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 12, Item 5)
    - Ravinia Festival, 1930-1979 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Houston
    - Houston Apollos vs. Tulsa Oilers Souvenir Program, 1967-68 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Houston Arts Calendar, 1983-84 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Houston Printed Materials (Box 8, Folder 16)
      - Houston Honors the Challenger Seven, March 27, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 16, Item 1)
      - Azalea Trail brochures (Box 8, Folder 16, Item 2)
      - Astro Polo (Box 8, Folder 16, Item 3)
    - The Stehlin Foundation for Cancer Research: "A Million Dollar Evening", 1983 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Periodicals
    - Arts Line, 1984-86 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Discover, October 1980 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Melody, June 1935/Popular Songs, June 1936 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - SHOW, October 1961 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Scrapbook
    - "Plays and Players-A Theatre Goer's Record" (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Society for the Performing Arts, 1980s
    - Newsletters, fliers, season listings, 1980s (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Oversize Collection
  - Opera
    Large collection of posters promoting Houston Grand Opera, New York, and other state and city opera productions. Regional posters are in alphabetical order by city or state then by production.
    - Program: Houston Grand Opera-20 Seasons (Box 1, Item 1)
    - Posters (Box 1)
      - Houston (Box 1)
        - The World of Gilbert and Sullivan, undated (Box 1, Item 2)
        - Candide (Box 1, Item 3)
      - Houston Grand Opera (Box 1)
        - The Merry Widow, undated (Box 1, Item 4)
        - HGO/Texas Opera Theater: Cosi fan Tutte, 1974 (Box 1, Item 5)
      - Regional U.S. (Box 1)
        - Associated Artists Opera Co: Bicentennial Season, 1975-76 (Box 1, Item 6)
        - Augusta Opera Association: Lucia di Lammermoor, undated (Box 1, Item 7)
        - Baltimore Opera 1976-77 Season (Box 1, Item 8)
        - Opera Company of Boston 1975 Season (Box 1, Item 9)
        - Boston Lyric Opera, 1983-84 (Box 1, Item 10)
        - Boston Lyric Opera: The Postman Always Rings Twice, 1994 (Box 1, Item 11)
        - Cincinnati: 62nd Season and 10 years at Music Hall, 1981-82 (Box 1, Item 12)
        - Colorado: Opera Association (Box 1, Item 13)
        - Delaware: The Last of the Mohicans, 1976 (Box 1, Item 14)
        - Des Moines: Metro Opera, 1982 (Box 1, Item 15)
        - Amahl and the Night Visitors (Kansas City), undated (Box 1, Item 16)
        - The Lyric (Kansas City), 1974 (Box 1, Item 17)
        - The Lyric (Kansas City), undated (Box 1, Item 18)
        - Kentucky Opera Association, 1971-72 (Box 1, Item 19)
        - Kentucky Opera Association, 1972-73 (Box 1, Item 20)
        - Kentucky Opera Association, 1974-75 (Box 1, Item 21)
        - The Bartered Bride (Madison Civic Opera), undated (Box 1, Item 22)
        - Carmen (Madison Civic Opera), 1981 (Box 1, Item 23)
        - Turandot (Madison Civic Opera), undated (Box 1, Item 24)
        - Madison Opera: Shining Brow, undated (Box 1, Item 25)
        - Greater Miami Opera, 1982-83 (Box 1, Item 26)
        - Chamber Opera Theatre (Milwaukee), undated (Box 1, Item 27)
        - Florentine Opera of Milwaukee 1992-93 Season (Box 1, Item 28)
        - The Center Opera Company of Minneapolis, The Mother of Us All, undated (Box 1, Item 29)
        - Minnesota Opera Company, The Voyage of Edgar Allan Poe, undated (Box 1, Item 30)
        - Diary of an African American (Box 1, Item 31)
        - Aida (Mississippi), undated (Box 1, Item 33)
        - Joan of Arc (Nevada Opera Guild), undated (Box 1, Item 34)
        - Joan of Arc, 20th Season (Box 1, Item 35)
        - Cosi fan Tutte (Opera New England), undated (Box 1, Item 36)
        - Voyage to the Moon (Opera New England), 1975 (Box 1, Item 37)
        - New Orleans Opera, undated (Box 1, Item 38)
        - New Mexico, 17th Season (Box 1, Item 39)
        - Chamber Opera Theatre of New York: The Bear (Box 1, Item 40)
        - Chamber Opera Theatre of New York: Angelique (Box 1, Item 41)
        - Light Opera of Manhattan: The Vagabond King, undated (Box 1, Item 42)
        - Light Opera of Manhattan: The Student Prince, undated (Box 1, Item 43)
        - Metropolitan Opera Company: Aida (Box 1, Item 44)
        - Metropolitan Opera Company: Faust (Box 1, Item 45)
        - Metropolitan Opera Company: La Traviata (Box 1, Item 46)
        - Metropolitan Opera Company: Lucia di Lammermoor (Box 1, Item 47)
        - Metropolitan Opera Company: Madame Butterfly (Box 1, Item 48)
        - Metropolitan Opera Company: Rigoletto (Box 1, Item 49)
        - New York City Opera: The Cunning Little Vixen, undated (Box 1, Item 50)
        - Omaha Opera, 1975-76 (Box 1, Item 51)
        - Die Fleidermaus (Portland Opera), 1976 (Box 1, Item 52)
        - Life of Orestes (Portland Opera), 1975 (Box 1, Item 53)
        - Il Barbiere di Siviglia (Portland Opera), 1976 (Box 1, Item 54)
        - Salome (Portland Opera), 1975 (Box 1, Item 55)
        - La Traviata (Portland Opera), 1975 (Box 1, Item 56)
        - Travels (Opera Roanoke), 1995 (Box 1, Item 57)
        - Porgy and Bess (Opera Roanoke), 1992 (Box 1, Item 58)
        - Sweeney Todd (Opera Roanoke), 1993 (Box 1, Item 59)
        - Rigoletto (San Francisco Opera), 1982 (Box 1, Item 60)
        - Western Opera Theater (Box 1, Item 61)
        - Seattle Opera: Der Ring des Nibelungen, 1984 (Box 1, Item 62)
        - The New Opera Memphis (Tennessee), 1983-84 (Box 1, Item 63)
        - Tosca (Tulsa), 1975 (Box 1, Item 64)
        - A Season of Revelry and Passion (Virginia Opera Association), 1982-83 (Box 1, Item 65)
        - Candide (Wisconsin) (Box 1, Item 66)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
      - Houston Grand Opera (Box 1)
        - The Barber of Seville (sketch) (Box 1, Item 67)
      - After Dinner Opera (Box 1)
        - When This You See, Remember Me, undated (Box 1, Item 68)
        - A Revolutionary Celebration, undated (Box 1, Item 69)
    - Autographed Memorabilia (Box 2)
      Mounted performance programs of HGO, photographs/autographs of cast members, identified on reverse
      - Houston Grand Opera (Box 2, Item 1)
        Mounted performance programs of HGO, photographs/autographs of cast members
    - Posters (Box 2)
      - Houston Grand Opera Posters (Box 2, Item 2)
      - Opera Singer Posters (Box 2, Item 3)
      - Houston Grand Opera Productions (Box 2, Item 4)
      - Texas Regional Opera Posters (Box 2, Item 5)
  - Dance
    Posters for performances held at Jones Hall for the Performing Arts and by Houston Ballet.
    - Posters (Box 3)
      - Bayanihan Philippine Dance Company, undated (Box 3, Item 1)
      - An Evening with Dame Margot Fonteyn, 1980 (Box 3, Item 2)
      - Les Ballets Trocadero de Monte Carlo, undated (Box 3, Item 3)
      - Radio City Music Hall: "5, 6, 7, 8 Dance!" (Box 3, Item 4)
      - (Society for the Performing Arts) Bella Lewitzky Dance Co. (Box 3, Item 5)
    - Jones Hall (Box 3)
      - Paul Taylor Dance Company, undated (Box 3, Item 6)
      - Feld Ballet, undated (Box 3, Item 7)
      - The Magnificent Mazowsze, undated (Box 3, Item 8)
      - The National Ballet of Canada, undated (Box 3, Item 9)
      - Peer Gynt (Houston Ballet) (Box 3, Item 10)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 5)
      - (Drawing for) cover Performing Arts Magazine, April 1980 (Box 5, Item 9)
  - Instrumental
    Posters for performances held at Jones Hall for the Performing Arts and Texas Chamber Orchestra.
    - Posters (Box 4)
      - Carnegie Hall: Centennial Season (Box 4, Item 1)
      - P.D.Q. Bach, undated (Box 4, Item 2)
      - Jones Hall (Box 4)
        - The Canadian Brass (Box 4, Item 3)
        - 1,000 years of Jazz (New Orleans Review) (Box 4, Item 4)
        - Itzhak Perlman (Box 4, Item 5)
        - James Galway (Box 4, Item 6)
        - Janina Fialkowska (Box 4, Item 7)
        - Mstislav Leopoldovich Rostropovich (Box 4, Item 8)
        - Orchestre de Paris (Box 4, Item 9)
        - The Philadelphia Orchestra, 1979-80 (Box 4, Item 10)
        - The Philharmonic Orchestra (Box 4, Item 11)
        - The Preservation Hall Jazz Band (Box 4, Item 12)
        - Texas Little Symphony, undated (Box 4, Item 13)
      - Texas Chamber Orchestra (Box 4)
        - All Texas-American Program (Conductor: Igor Buketoff) (Box 4, Item 14)
        - Brittan, Mozart, Dvorak (Conductor: John DeMain) (Box 4, Item 15)
        - Stravinsky (Conductor: Michael Moores) (Box 4, Item 16)
        - Bach, Mozart, Barber, Hayden (Conductor: Ronal Braunstein) (Box 4, Item 17)
        - Mozart & Vivaldi (Sergiu Luca) (Box 4, Item 18)
  - Theatre
    This collection contains posters for Alley Theatre, Main Street Theater, Stages, Texas Theatre Under the Stars performances, an invitation to Alley Theatre Gala, and two programs for musical theatre.
    - Invitation: Alley Theatre Gala, 1986 (Box 4, Item 19)
    - Posters (Box 4)
      - Theatre Three Dallas: Second Stage Festival, 1980 (Box 4, Item 25)
      - Equinox Theatre: Why Hanna's skirt Won't Stay Down and Who Killed my Bald Sister Sophie?, 1980 (Box 4, Item 26)
      - Miller Outdoor Theatre: The Vagabond King (Box 4, Item 27)
      - Alley Theatre (Box 4)
        - Out at Sea, undated (Box 4, Item 20)
        - Galileo, 1968-69 (Box 4, Item 21)
        - Ring Round the Bathtub, undated (Box 4, Item 22)
        - Indians, 1975 (Box 4, Item 23)
        - Repertory Spectacular, 1982 (Box 4, Item 24)
      - Main Street Theater (Box 4)
        - The Philadephia Story, undated (Box 4, Item 28)
        - Tintypes, 1982 (Box 4, Item 29)
        - Women and Men, undated (Box 4, Item 30)
        - Travesties, undated (Box 4, Item 31)
        - Caesar and Cleopatra, 1983 (Box 4, Item 32)
        - Old Times, undated (Box 4, Item 33)
        - "There goes the neighborhood" Main Street Theatre (Box 4, Item 34)
      - Stages (Box 4)
        - The Importance of Being Earnest (Box 4, Item 35)
        - Texas Playwrights Festival, 1983 (Box 4, Item 36)
      - Texas Theatre Under the Stars (Box 4)
        - 1983-84 Season (Box 4, Item 37)
        - Sugar, 1985 (Box 4, Item 38)
        - Paint Your Wagon, 1984 (Box 4, Item 39)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 4)
        - Marsha Norman: reception, opening night performance of Getting Out (Box 4, Item 40)
        - Show Boat, undated (Box 4, Item 41)
        - Side by Side, undated (Box 4, Item 42)
    - Programs (Box 4)
      - 42nd Street, 1984 (Box 4, Item 43)
      - Starlight Express, 1984 (Box 4, Item 44)
  - Miscellaneous
    Posters, periodicals, an architectural drawing for Houston Grand Opera production and 2 collages are included in this series.
    - Periodical: Performing Arts Magazine (Box 5)
      - Cover art samples for Performing Arts (Box 5, Item 1)
      - Cover layouts, Performing Arts, Feb. 1979-July 1980 (Box 5, Item 2)
      - October 1977 (Box 5, Item 3)
      - November 1977 (Box 5, Item 4)
      - February 1979 (Box 5, Item 5)
      - December 1979 (Box 5, Item 6)
    - Posters (Box 5)
      - Houston (Box 5)
        - Houston Festival, 1980 (Box 5, Item 7)
        - Houston Festival, 1983 (Box 5, Item 8)
        - Bayou Show, Houston Festival, 1983 (Box 5, Item 9)
        - "Houston," Natural Gas Corporation, 1976 (Box 5, Item 10)
        - "Houston," Natural Gas Corporation, 1979 (Box 5, Item 11)
        - Sumfest (Cultural Arts Council of Houston), 1981 (Box 5, Item 12)
      - Exhibitions (Box 5)
        - Pauline Howard and Harris Gallery, 1981 (Box 5, Item 13)
        - Rosemary Mahoney, 1981 (Box 5, Item 14)
        - Video/Multi-image (Sensory Communications for the 80s), 1981 (Box 5, Item 15)
        - Meredith Long and Company: Houston Ballet, 1982 (Box 5, Item 16)
        - Artists and the Theatre, 1982 (Box 5, Item 17)
        - Art and Our City Lecture Series (Box 5, Item 18)
      - Performances (Box 5)
        - The Comedy Workshop: The Two Bit Opera, undated (Box 5, Item 19)
        - Entertainment Troupe and Traveling Show (Tennessee), undated (Box 5, Item 20)
        - Marcel Marceau, undated (Box 5, Item 21)
        - Massenkoff Russian Folk Festival, undated (Box 5, Item 22)
        - Original Silver Cornet Band musical celebration and band concert (Tennessee) (Box 5, Item 23)
        - Jones Hall: Vienna Boys' Choir, 1983 (Box 5, Item 24)
        - New York: Moss, undated (Box 5, Item 25)
      - Radio (Box 5)
        - KODA 99FM, undated (Box 5, Item 26)
        - KLEF The New Season, undated (Box 5, Item 27)
    - Architectural Drawing (Box 5)
      - Scene design for Houston Grand Opera production of Othello, May 1, 1975 (Box 5, Item 28)
    - Collages (Box 5)
      - 2 collages inscribed to Kaplan from artist Michel Bezman, 1983 (Box 5, Item 29)